Harry J. Blacklidge papers, 1917-1947
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Harry J. Blacklidge papers, 1917-1947
AZ 211
Blacklidge, Harry J.
The collection includes letters, work cards, two photographs, newspaper clippings, and various printed materials concerning the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners in America, Local No. 857; chiefly newspaper clippings concerning construction in the Tucson area, 1926-1927. Also includes papers relating to the formation of the apprenticeship training program in Arizona.
.1 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL:http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Harry Blacklidge was a carpenter. As a member of the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners in America, Local No. 857, he served as chairman of various committees.
Organization
This collection is organized into two series:
Series I: Union Material, 1917-1941
Series II: Apprenticeship Training Material, 1947
Scope and Content Note
The collection includes letters, work cards, two photographs, newspaper clippings, and various printed materials concerning the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners in America, Local No. 857; chiefly newspaper clippings concerning construction in the Tucson area, 1926-1927. Also includes papers relating to the formation of the apprenticeship training program in Arizona.
Access Terms
United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America. Local Union No. 857 (Tucson, Ariz.)
Labor unions -- Arizona
Labor -- Arizona
Apprentices -- Arizona
Building trades -- Arizona
Labor movement -- Arizona
Working class -- Arizona
Correspondence
News clippings
Photographs
Separated Material
Newspaper clippings and some photographs were removed and cataloged separately.
Container List
- Series I: Union Material, 1917-1941
  - Harry J. Blacklidge dues book. 1921-1924 (Box 1)
  - Working cards from the Building Trades Department. 1918-1923 (Box 1)
  - Working card from Local 857. 3rd quarter, 1925 (Box 1)
  - Blacklidge's business cards. One lists contractor on the back. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence from Harold Hanover to Secretary Duffy regarding 40th Anniversary. May 28, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence regarding 40th Anniversary. June 26, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence regarding a banquet photograph which was going to be published in Carpenter. June 26, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence from Frank Duffy promising to attend Labor Day. July 9, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence regarding an account of Labor Day which was going to be published in the December issue of Carpenter. November 13, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Photographs of Frank Duffy and Abe Muir. (Box 1)
    Frank Duffy was a long time General Secretary of United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Builders of America. Abe Muir was a famed general organizer for the United Brotherhood.
  - Copy of Carpenter, with a photo of the 40th Anniversary banquet. August 1941 (Box 1)
  - Program of the 27th Convention at Prescott. September 18, 1938-September 20, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence from Blacklidge, a plea for "buy at home." April 9, 1919 (Box 1)
  - Article of erection of Red Cross Hut at the South Pacific Depot. ca. 1917 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook of Tucson construction. December 1926-August 1927 (Box 1)
  - Loose leaf scrapbook of Tucson construction. August 1927-December 1927 (Box 1)
  - Constitution and by-laws of the AFL-CIO merge State Federation. 1921-1924 (Box 1)
- Series II: Apprenticeship Training Material, 1947
  - File of materials documenting the beginning of the Apprenticeship Training Program. 1947 (Box 1)